Vansh Mehta

Mobile No.: +971-525972991

Email- vanshmehta47@gmail.com

Linked In- https://www.linkedin.com/in/vansh-mehta-a1b2a4112/



OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a fulfilling position as System Engineer and support of all IT needs that offers growth opportunities and allows me to utilize my leadership skills and experience.

PROFFESIONAL SUMMARY:

Over 8 years of progressive experience in Network Protocols, Communication Network and Firewalls. Comprehensive Cisco technology knowledge in designing, implementation, administration and support. In-depth knowledge of deploying IP protocols and troubleshooting. Experienced in layer 2 switching and 3 routing. Proficient in usage of Microsoft VISIO as tools for technical presentation and documentation. Extensive experience in Planning, Implementation, Configuring, Testing and Troubleshooting of networking system. Competent in handling escalating problems.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

• Presently working at Madenat Recycling Company Jebel Ali Dubai as Senior IT Support engineer, since 11th July 2018.

Job Responsibilities/ Duties

- Administering & designing LANs, WANs internet/intranet, and voice networks. Analysing & developing key components using methodology prescribed techniques.
- Communicating and negotiating with users, specialists, other staff and suppliers.
- Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, tracert, telnet. Responsible for communication protocols, configuration, integration & security.
- Investigating, diagnosing and resolve all network problems.
- Maintaining pre-packaged software applications on the LAN.
- Upgrading and repairing faults on CIS systems, networks & peripheral equipment.
- Cisco & HP switch configuration in particular VLAN configuration/troubleshooting.
- Working with multiple technical platforms i.e. mainframe, two-tiered client-servers and three-tiered client-servers.
- Worked at Reliance Industries HN Hospital Mumbai as IT Support engineer, since November 2016 till June 2018.
- Worked at Raj InfoTech as resident engineer at SPCL life science pvt limited, since Oct'2014 until October 2016.
- Worked with Ambe Technology, Vadodara, India since April 2012 to Sep 2014 as IT supports team and Network Engineer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Hardware:

- Installation of Processor, Motherboard, & all parts.
- Configuring all the parts and Assembling & Disassembling.
- Troubleshooting of all the parts of Hardware.
- Installation of Laptop Parts & Repairing.

Operating System (Client):

- Installation of Win. XP, Vista, 7, 8, 10.
- Installation of Linux & Red hat
- Configuring Network Troubleshooting in Client OS.
- Configuring Security like Firewall, Phishing Filter.
- System Backup & Restore Etc.

Operating System (Server):

- Installation of Win. Server 2003 & 08.
- Exchange Server 2007 & 2010
- Configuring & Managing DHCP & DNS Roles.
- Configuring Wireless Networking.
- Configuring Server Backup.

Networking:

- Installing & Configuring Hub, Modem & Networking Switch.
- Installing & Configuring Wired & Wireless Router.
- Solution of IP Addressing.
- Configuring Ad-hoc & Extension point Network.
- Crimping Straight-through & Crossover Cables.
- Punching of I/O.

ACADEMIC CERTIFICATION:

- Diploma in computer science and computer engineering.
- Cisco Certified Network Associate from Zabeel Institute of Management & Technology Dubai, UAE.
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist & MCSE from Zabeel Institute of Management & Technology Dubai, UAE
- Microsoft Certified System Engineer from Zabeel Institue of Management & Technology Dubai, UAE
- Hardware & Networking Engineer certified from N-Power Aptech Vadodara, India
- Exchange server 2007 & 2010, MCTIP server 2008 from Rolla institute of management Dubai.

QUALIFICATIONS:

- Network Management
- Platforms and Routing Protocols
- Programming language and Operating Systems
- Infrastructure services and LAN technologies
- Port and WAN technologies

LINGUISTIC PROFICIENCY:

• Fluent in English, Hindi, Gujarati - speaking, reading and writing

PERSONAL DETAILS:

• Date of Birth: September 2, 1991

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that above given information is true and to the best of my knowledge.

Vansh Mehta